Now let's get started shall we.
In order for any programmer to learn a language there are four key things that you need to really master
for any sort of language including python.
First are the terms of that language.
Sometimes a programming language has different awards and different definitions for these words that
you're going to have to memorize things like statements variables instantiation really complicated sounding
words but you need to understand what they mean so that you can talk to other programmers.
You also need to learn about a languages data type that is what sort of data can a program hold.
You can think of it as a values just like in real life.
We have different ways to represent values like numbers letters and symbols.
In programming we have these data types to store information and each programming language has different
sort of data types.
Next we need to learn about actions.
At the end of the day all programming is is a way for us to tell our machines Hey store this data and
then retrieve this data and perform some action on it.
That's all it is just using memory and performing some actions.
So we're going to learn how to perform those actions and then finally we have to learn the best practices
of each language.
There's good ways of writing Python code and then there's bad ways so that when we build our applications
our programs while we don't have a leaning tower like this but we have a solid structure and a solid
program.
So throughout the course we're going to learn about these things but keep this in mind.
These four things are why you need to become a good programmer and I want to start the basic Python
section with the data types.
So let's get started.